Francis J. O' Malley Papers
University of Notre Dame Archives
- Francis J. O'Malley: Manuscripts, CFOM
  - Financial Records and Personal Documents, 1928-1974; CFOM 23-25/; Tax records, commencement programs, academic degrees, awards, newspaper clippings relating to Malley's activities, his undergraduate grade reports, and similar items.
    - Miscellany, CFOM 25/03
      - "Colloquium Members," handwritten (not by O'Malley) note, CFOM 25/03
    - Notre Dame Students in Peru (CILA, circa 1963?), pictures, CFOM 25/04; Also minutes of a meeting
    - Edwin O'Connor, CFOM 25/05
      - Letter from his widow, Mary E. O'Connor, April 28, 1968., CFOM 25/05
      - Newspaper clippings re: Edwin O'Connor, CFOM 25/05
      - Galley Proofs (two pages) from unidentified work, CFOM 25/05
      - Letter from Veniette ________ to Frank O'Malley, Oct. 27, 1969., CFOM 25/05
      - The Atlantic, Vol. 224, No. 4, October 1969: Includes "The Great Baldini: A Memoir and a Collaboration," by Edmund Wilson and Edwin O'Connor, CFOM 25/05
      - The Atlantic, Vol. 214, No. 6, December 1964: Includes "One Spring Morning," by Edwin O'Connor (opening episode of then untitled novel), CFOM 25/05
    - Elmer Andrew Steffen, Song Folio, present to O'Malley, CFOM 25/06
    - Fred Schwartz memorial volume, Part of Forever is Better than None (1970), CFOM 25/07; Cover letter attached from Rev. Edmund P. Joyce to Frank O'Malley, September 29, 1970.
    - The Wranglers of Notre Dame, constitution, CFOM 25/08
    - O'Malley Project: Article from Yves R. Simon's Civilisation Americaine, 1950, CFOM 25/09
    - Lecture notes from Francis O'Malley's Philosophy of Literature class (Donated by Rev. Joseph Keena), CFOM 29/01
    - Talk on WSBT Radio "That Which Demoralizes Us" (taken from College of Arts and Letters Associate Dean Plunkett files), CFOM 29/02
    - Photocopy of a typewritten transcript of a letter from John Henry Newman to Henry William Wilberforce, 9 July 1827, CFOM 30/08
    - Subject Files, CFOM 31/01-07
  - Restricted Material, 1932-1974; CFOM 14-22/
    - Course Outline and Record Books (Restricted), 1939-1958; CFOM 14/
      - Christian Education "The Christian School of the Humanities," 1958 course outline, CFOM 14/01
      - Class Record Book, 1939-42 Class Record Book, 1945-46 Class Record Book, 1958-62, CFOM 14/02
    - Student Papers (Restricted), 1940s-1974; CFOM 16-22/; Poems, short stories, and critical essays written as assignments for O'Malley's English courses, including Rhetoric and Composition, Modern Catholic Writers, and Philosophy of Literature. Additional student papers are filed with other background material for O'Malley`s lectures (Boxes 10-13). The student papers are RESTRICTED.
      - Banchoff, Thomas, CFOM 16/01
      - Unidentified author, "Darlin' Jane" found inside journal by Thomas Banchoff (folder #1 above), CFOM 16/02
      - Barrett, Sister Anne Maurice, CFOM 16/03
      - Bill, G. Anthony, CFOM 16/04
      - Brislin, Tom, CFOM 16/05
      - Chandonia, Ronald Paul, CFOM 16/06
      - Cook, Kelly, CFOM 16/07
      - Delaney, Tom, CFOM 16/08
      - Dell, William Francis, CFOM 16/09
      - Evans, F. Fallon, CFOM 16/10
      - Fornelli, Francis J., CFOM 16/11
      - Frayne, T., CFOM 16/12
      - Griffith, William, CFOM 16/13
      - Hessler, J.G., CFOM 16/14
      - Hillebrand, Joseph R., CFOM 16/15
      - Kenton, Jeffrey J., CFOM 16/16
      - Kohl, Gerard Daniel, CFOM 16/17
      - Labdik, George F., I, CFOM 17/01
      - Labdik, George F., II, CFOM 17/02
      - McCarthy, John, CFOM 18/01
      - McNeill, Robert, CFOM 18/02
      - Moran, John K., Jr., CFOM 18/03
      - Newman, James, CFOM 18/03A
      - O'Grady, William Walsh, Jr., CFOM 18/04
      - O'Mahoney, Sister Sheila de Paul, CFOM 18/05
      - Pfaff, William, CFOM 18/06
      - Reishman, John V., CFOM 18/07
      - Ryan, Chuck, CFOM 18/08
      - Smith, Nan, CFOM 18/09
      - Tiernan, Robert James, CFOM 18/10
      - Witwer, Wallace F., CFOM 18/11
      - Student Papers, 1946-1949 (Modern Catholic Writers), CFOM 19/01
      - Student Papers and Exams, 1963-1964, CFOM 19/02
      - Student Papers, Spring 1964 (English 12: Rhetoric and Composition), CFOM 19/03
      - Student Papers, Spring 1966 (English 12: Rhetoric and Composition), CFOM 19/04
      - Student Papers, Spring 1969 (English 12: Rhetoric and Composition), CFOM 19/05
      - Student Papers, Spring 1969 (Modern Catholic Writers), CFOM 19/06
      - Student Papers, Fall 1970 (Philosophy of Literature), Unidentified and A-H, CFOM 20/01
      - Student Papers, Fall 1070 (Philosophy of Literature), K-W, CFOM 20/02
      - Student Papers, Winter 1971, CFOM 20/03
      - Student Papers, Spring 1971, CFOM 20/04
      - Student Papers, Spring 1971; Freshman Seminar, Spring 1972, CFOM 20/05
      - Student Papers, May 1972 (Modern Catholic Writers), CFOM 20/06
      - Student Papers, Spring 1972 (Modern Catholic Writers), CFOM 20/07
      - Student Poems, submitted by O'Malley to America, April, 1973; CFOM 21/01
      - Student Papers, Spring 1973 (Modern Catholic Writers), A-M, CFOM 21/02
      - Student Papers, Spring 1973 (Modern Catholic Writers), N-Z, CFOM 21/03
      - Student Papers, Fall 1973 (Philosophy of Literature), A-K, CFOM 22/01
      - Student Papers, Fall 1973 (Philosophy of Literature), L-W, CFOM 22/02
      - Student Papers, Fall 1973, CFOM 22/03
      - Student Papers, Spring 1974, CFOM 22/04
      - Student Papers, 1970-1974?, CFOM 22/05
      - Student Paper, non-dated (Modern Catholic Writers), CFOM 22/06
      - Student papers, CFOM 31/08-10
    - Correspondence (Restricted), 1932-1974; CFOM 26-28/, 30/; Correspondence with collegues, former students, writers, and others. Topics discussed include literary topics, aca demic and administrative activities relating to Notre Dame, O'Malley's work with the Danforth and Woodrow Wilson Founda- tions, his attempts to enlist in the military during WWII, and the activities of former students. Principal correspondents include Desmond Fitzgerald, Thomas Banchoff, Edward Georner, Willa Cather, and Jacques Maritain. Most of the correspond ence are letters received by O'Malley, few of his letters to others are included. The correspondence series is RESTRICTED.
      - Correspondence: Non-dated, CFOM 26/01
      - Correspondence: 1932-1940, CFOM 26/02
      - Correspondence: 1941-1943, CFOM 26/03
      - Correspondence: 1944-1947, CFOM 26/04
      - Correspondence: 1948-1952, CFOM 26/05
      - Correspondence: 1953-1959, CFOM 26/06
      - Correspondence: 1960-1963, CFOM 26/07
      - Correspondence: 1964-1968, CFOM 26/08
      - Correspondence: 1969-1973, CFOM 26/09
      - Correspondence: O'Malley (draft: 26 April 1936) and Hugh S. Taylor (response: 18 May 1936), CFOM 26/10
      - Correspondence: Desmond Fitzgerald to O'Malley (non-dated and 1936-1940); and Bernard Wall to Desmond Fitzgerald (2 April no year), CFOM 26/11
      - Correspondence: Willa Cather to O'Malley, 1938-1939, CFOM 26/12
      - Correspondence: Jacques Maritain to O'Malley, 4 October 1944, CFOM 26/13
      - Laymen's Liberal Education College, 1945-1947, CFOM 26/14
      - Laymen's Liberal Education College, CFOM 26/15
      - Laymen's Liberal Education College, 1947, CFOM 26/16
      - Correspondence: Edward Goerner to Frank O'Malley, 1951-1953; CFOM 26/17
      - Correspondence: O'Malley drafts of letters to Edward Goerner, non-dated (circa 1952), CFOM 26/18
      - Correspondence: O'Malley, 24 August 1952, to Ed ?, CFOM 26/19
      - Correspondence: O'Malley drafts of letters, 1952, CFOM 26/20
      - Correspondence: William T. Kirby to Frank O'Malley, 22 March 1954 re: Clarence Manion, CFOM 27/01
      - Correspondence: Hannah Arendt to Frank O'Malley, 29 November 1954, CFOM 27/02
      - Correspondence to O'Malley, 1952-1955?, CFOM 27/03
      - Correspondence: Humanities Course, Summer 1957, O'Malley and Caponigri, CFOM 27/04
      - Committee on Academic Progress (Superior Students Program): notes and correspondence, 1956-1958, CFOM 27/05
      - Correspondence and Speech re: Coach Brennan and Education (by James Carberry), 1959 and ?, CFOM 27/06
      - Danforth Association Fellowships, 1958-1963, CFOM 27/07
      - Rhodes Scholarship Program, 1962, CFOM 27/08
      - Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Nominations, 1956-1963, CFOM 27/09
      - Correspondence: 1961-1963, CFOM 27/10
      - Correspondence and Reprints, mostly 1961-1963, CFOM 27/11
      - Correspondence re: J.F. Kennedy assassination, 22 & 23 Nov 1963, CFOM 27/12
      - Correspondence: O'Malley to Rev. Charles McCarragher re: The Juggler, 11 March 1967, CFOM 27/13
      - Correspondence: George Lensing to O'Malley, 3 July 1968, CFOM 27/14
      - Correspondence: O'Malley to Ideal Baldoni, 26 November re: 1968 election proceedings on campus, CFOM 27/15
      - Correspondence: Paul R. Bryne to O'Malley, 22 June 1970, CFOM 27/16
      - Student letters of appreciation, 1952, 1973, and non-dated, CFOM 27/17
      - Correspondence: Tom Kapacinska to O'Malley, non-dated, re: William Blake, CFOM 27/18
      - O'Malley drafts, non-dated, CFOM 27/19
      - Non- O'Malley Miscellaneous, CFOM 27/20
      - Lil Fahey to Frank O'Malley, 26 September 1968, CFOM 27/21
      - Thomas F. Banchoff to Francis O'Malley, CFOM 28
        - Banchoff correspondence, undated - September 1960 - "Religion, Higher Education, and the Life of the Mind: Education in the Nation's Service," Thomas F. Banchoff, May 9, 1960., CFOM 28/01
        - Banchoff correspondence, October 1960 - February 1961, 1960-1961; CFOM 28/02
        - Banchoff correspondence, March - May, 1961; CFOM 28/03
        - Banchoff correspondence, September 1961 - December 1962, 1961-1962; CFOM 28/04
        - Banchoff correspondence, January - June, 1970; CFOM 28/05
        - Banchoff correspondence, July - December, 1970; CFOM 28/06
        - Banchoff correspondence; attached: untitled poem attached: envelope with O'Malley notes, 1971; CFOM 28/07
        - Banchoff correspondence, 1972; CFOM 28/08
        - Banchoff correspondence, 1973-1974; CFOM 28/09
        - Correspondence: O'Malley / Thomas Banchoff, rough drafts, CFOM 28/10
        - Closed Banchoff Correspondence: 1960-1961 and March 1972, CFOM 28/11
      - Correspondence, 1952, 1962-1970s; CFOM 30/01
      - Correspondence, 1952, 1962-1970s; CFOM 30/02
      - Correspondence, 1952, 1962-1970s; CFOM 30/03
- Francis J. O' Malley: Audio-Visual Material, AFOM
  - Frank O'Malley - T.S. Eliot's Ash Wednesday; Hymn to the Church [was AFOMC 2877], AFOM E22
  - Frank O'Malley - Poems by Gerard Manley Hopkins: Wreck of the Deutschland; God's Grandeur; the Windhover; Spring and Fall [was AFOMC 2878], AFOM E23
  - Frank O'Malley albums - Carl Sanburg (poor quality), AFOM C2877-2881
  - Francis J. O'Malley - Ash Wednesday, Hymn to the Church, Wreck of the Deutschland, God's Grandeur [copy of AFOM E22-23], AFOM 8566
  - Copy of 78 RPM records - Carl Sandburg, AFOM A1488
  - Poems by Gerard Manley Hopkins [was AFOMC 2879], AFOM F20
  - Carl Sandburg [was AFOMC 2880-2881], AFOM F21-22
- Francis J. O'Malley: Graphics, GFOM
  - Portrait of Rev. Paul Maclone of Somerville, c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Portrait of Francis (Frank) O'Malley, CHS Class of 1928, c1928; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing outside with mail in his hands, c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing outside of Main Building, c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing outside with paper rolled up in his hands, 1940/0515; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing in an office (dorm apartment?) holding a book, 1943/0205; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley sitting in a chair in an office (dorm apartment?), c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley sitting in a chair in an office (dorm apartment?) [3 photos], 1945/0307; GFOM 1/01
  - Portrait of Francis (Frank) O'Malley in a metal frame; photo by Photomatic, International Mutoscope Corporation photo booth, c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing next to a window, reading a paper. Inscribed "Frank O'Malley - BEST MAN" on the back from Teddy and Anne, 1969/1025; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley sitting on a bar stool in someone's home, c1960s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley sitting in a chair in an office (dorm apartment?), 1943/0205; GFOM 1/01
  - Portrait of Francis (Frank) O'Malley, c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing outside, 1942/0618; GFOM 1/01
  - Casual close-up portraits of Francis (Frank) O'Malley [3 photos], c1940s; GFOM 1/01
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley at a party? with two men and two women, c1960s; GFOM 1/02
  - Commencement - Rev. Theodore M. Hesburgh presenting Francis (Frank) O'Malley with an honorary degree inside Notre Dame Stadium, 1957/0602; GFOM 1/02
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing in an office (Lyons Hall dorm apartment?), c1940s; GFOM 1/02
  - Portrait of Francis (Frank) O'Malley's head surrounded by books and four Sisters in the background; drawing by B. Hilarion, CSC, GFOM 1/03
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley speaking to a group of students in a lounge (classroom?) with a cigarette in hand [2 photos], c1950s; GFOM 1/04
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley speaking from a podium; photo by Ernesto Sol [grainy], c1960s; GFOM 1/04
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing in front of a chalkboard in a classroom, 1941/0531; GFOM 1/04
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Francis, age 13-14, in tree or bush at Clamshell Pond, Camp Wanocksett, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Photograph of the painting "The Old King" by Georges Rouault, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Two young girls sitting on a couch, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Two older men and a woman standing outside, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Interior view of Francis (Frank) O'Malley's office (dorm apartment?), 1942/0307; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Three women and three girls outside, c1950s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of niece Mary Lou; photo by Mantine, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of baby Christian, six and a half months, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Three boys and a girl sitting under a Christmas tree with a race track, 1966-1967; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley and an older woman inside of a house, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley in a house with an older woman and young woman, c1960s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family Christmas photos [4 photos], c1950s; GFOM 1/05
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of C.J. Kirby in a Navy uniform; photo by E. Zuniga, New York City, c1940s; GFOM 1/06
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of J.T. Kirby, c1940s; GFOM 1/06
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of niece Ellen, c1960s; GFOM 1/06
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family at a wedding, standing behind the cake with the bride, groom, and two women (mothers of the couple?), c1960s; GFOM 1/06
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley with another woman and baby Maura on her christening day, c1960s; GFOM 1/07
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of Dolly Kirby; photo by Takagi Studio, Great Neck, New York, c1940s; GFOM 1/07
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley Family - Portrait of "Groucho" (?) Kirby in Navy uniform; photo by Moffett, Chicago, c1940s; GFOM 1/07
  - C. MacDougal wedding party including Francis (Frank) O'Malley in the Lady Chapel of the Basilica of the Sacred Heart, 1951; GFOM 1/08
  - Copy of President Dwight D. Eisenhower's honorary degree [print of GPHR co/0127], 1960; GFOM 1/08
  - Review of Politics Editors Matthew Fitzsimons, Rev. Thomas McAvoy, and Francis (Frank) O'Malley by the Reflecting Pool of the Memorial Library (later Hesburgh Library [2 photos; prints of GPHR 45/4801], c1963; GFOM 1/08
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley standing with another man whose eyes are closed, c1960s; GFOM 1/08
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley and two other men sitting outside in the yard of a house, c1940s; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley posed with Jim Yoch family members outside of their house in Glendale, Missouri [3 photos], 1962-1963; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley and three other men drinking beer on the porch of a house, c1960s; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley teaching male students in a classroom, c1940s; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley overseeing male students taking a test/exam in a classroom, c1940s; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley with Mrs. John Kirby, 1969; GFOM 1/09
  - Memorial Library (Hesburgh Library) Dedication - Faculty lined up along the Reflecting Pool, which has ROTC? military members posted around, 1964; GFOM 1/09
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley with another man in his dorm room apartment, 1951/0318; GFOM 1/09
  - English Majors' party outside, including playing baseball, Professor Rufus Ranch, George Miles with a toddler, 1941/0531; GFOM 1/10
  - A bride posed in front of a fireplace with Christmas decorations, c1940s; GFOM 1/11
  - A bride and her other posed in front of a fireplace with Christmas decorations, c1940s; GFOM 1/11
  - A bride posed in front of a fireplace, c1940s; GFOM 1/11
  - A maid of honor? posed in front of a fireplace, c1940s; GFOM 1/11
  - John F. O'Dea in a military uniform, standing in front of a painting portrait of Francis (Frank) O'Malley, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley with a beer, sitting on a house porch railing, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - A backyard garden, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley and another man sitting on the porch of a house, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - View of a residential street, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - A woman standing next to a car in front of a house, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - A woman sitting in a car in front of a house, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - Francis (Frank) O'Malley sitting under a tree in a residential neighborhood, c1960s; GFOM 1/12
  - CILA (Council for International Lay Apostolate) group in Peru, includes with Rev. Edward "Monk" Malloy in a monogram jacket [32 photos], 1963; GFOM 1/13
  - O'Malley, Francis- photographs of speaking engagements, GFOM 1/02
  - O'Malley, Francis- family, GFOM 1/03
  - O'Malley, Francis- pictured with others, GFOM 1/04-05
  - McDougal Wedding, 1951; GFOM 1/04
  - Rufus Rauch- English Majors, GFOM 1/06
  - Miles, George, GFOM 1/06
  - miscellaneous photographs, GFOM 1/07
  - miscellaneous photographs, GFOM 1/08